let questions = [
    {
        numb: 1,
        question: "What is Node.js primarily suitable for?",
        answer: "C. Developing highly scalable back-end services",
        options: [
            "A. Building front-end interfaces",
            "B. Creating CPU-intensive applications",
            "C. Developing highly scalable back-end services",
            "D. Designing mobile applications"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 2,
        question: "In Node.js, what is used to handle all requests efficiently?",
        answer: "B. Single thread",
        options: [
            "A. Multiple threads",
            "B. Single thread",
            "C. Forked processes",
            "D. Task queues"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        question: "How does Node.js handle CPU-intensive applications?",
        answer: "D. Not suitable for CPU-intensive applications",
        options: [
            "A. Efficiently",
            "B. In parallel",
            "C. Slowly",
            "D. Not suitable for CPU-intensive applications"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4,
        question: "What type of applications is Node.js ideal for building?",
        answer: "A. Data-intensive and real-time applications",
        options: [
            "A. Data-intensive and real-time applications",
            "B. Offline applications",
            "C. Single-page applications",
            "D. Graphic-intensive applications"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5,
        question: "In Node.js, what replaces the window object?",
        answer: "C. Global object",
        options: [
            "A. Document object",
            "B. Navigator object",
            "C. Global object",
            "D. Window variable"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6,
        question: "What does every file in Node.js act as?",
        answer: "C. Module",
        options: [
            "A. Class",
            "B. Function",
            "C. Module",
            "D. Object"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7,
        question: "How can module functions be made public in Node.js?",
        answer: "C. Exporting them",
        options: [
            "A. Using constants",
            "B. Declaring globally",
            "C. Exporting them",
            "D. Assigning to global variables"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8,
        question: "What does the Node.js OS module provide?",
        answer: "B. System information ",
        options: [
            "A. Access to external databases",
            "B. System information ",
            "C. File handling functions",
            "D. Network operations"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9,
        question: "How are asynchronous methods in Node.js typically handled?",
        answer: "C. Using a callback function",
        options: [
            "A. Synchronously",
            "B. Using promises",
            "C. Using a callback function",
            "D. In parallel"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10,
        question: "What is the core functionality of Node.js based on?",
        answer: "C. Events ",
        options: [
            "A. Promises",
            "B. Callbacks",
            "C. Events ",
            "D. Asynchronous operations"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11,
        question: "How can listener functions in Node.js receive data for an event?",
        answer: "B. By accessing the event object ",
        options: [
            "A. Through global variables",
            "B. By accessing the event object ",
            "C. Via callback functions",
            "D. By invoking another function"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 12,
        question: "How can a custom class with additional capabilities be created in Node.js?",
        answer: "C. By inheriting from the Event Emitter ",
        options: [
            "A. By extending the Node.js core",
            "B. By creating a new module",
            "C. By inheriting from the Event Emitter ",
            "D. By declaring additional functions"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 13,
        question: "What kind of events does a Node.js server typically raise?",
        answer: "D. New connection or request events ",
        options: [
            "A. Timer events",
            "B. Exception events",
            "C. I/O events",
            "D. New connection or request events "
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 14,
        question: "What is used in Node.js to create a structured way of handling routes?",
        answer: "C. Express framework",
        options: [
            "A. Custom modules",
            "B. Event Emitter",
            "C. Express framework",
            "D. OS module"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 15,
        question: "How does Node.js handle HTTP requests?",
        answer: "B. Using a single thread",
        options: [
            "A. Using multiple threads",
            "B. Using a single thread",
            "C. Creating child processes",
            "D. Relying on external libraries"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 16,
        question: "What coding paradigm does Node.js primarily follow?",
        answer: "C. Asynchronous programming",
        options: [
            "A. Functional programming",
            "B. Object-oriented programming",
            "C. Asynchronous programming",
            "D. Sequential programming"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 17,
        question: "What is an important feature of Node.js that enables efficient event-driven programming?",
        answer: "C. Event loop",
        options: [
            "A. Callback chaining",
            "B. Error handling",
            "C. Event loop",
            "D. Microservices"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 18,
        question: "How does Node.js handle scalability in applications?",
        answer: "D. By utilizing non-blocking I/O operations",
        options: [
            "A. By using multithreading",
            "B. By load balancing across multiple servers",
            "C. By optimizing CPU usage",
            "D. By utilizing non-blocking I/O operations"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 19,
        question: "What role does the package.json file play in Node.js projects?",
        answer: "A. It defines project dependencies and scripts",
        options: [
            "A. It defines project dependencies and scripts",
            "B. It stores user interface configurations",
            "C. It manages database connections",
            "D. It controls the server routing"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 20,
        question: "What is the primary role of the 'package.json' file in Node.js projects?",
        answer: "A. It defines project dependencies and scripts",
        options: [
            "A. It defines project dependencies and scripts",
            "B. It handles user authentication",
            "C. It manages server configurations",
            "D. It controls client-side routing"
        ]
    }
];
